<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>factor on 𝔂𝓾𝓼𝓴𝓪𝓶</title>
		<link>https://yusbk.github.io/tags/factor/</link>
		<description>Recent content in factor </description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		
  		<language>en</language>
		
		<managingEditor>Page(/tags/factor) (Yusman Kamaleri)</managingEditor>
    	
  		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
		<atom:link href="/tags/factor/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Smerge, ediff and diff</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/11/09/magit-ediff/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 15:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/11/09/magit-ediff/</guid>
			<description>First published: 2021-04-30
For enditing conflict in git, use smerge or ediff.
Smerge Basic workflow:
 Open magit status with SPC g g in Doom Identify the mark with Unmerged under Unstage list Go to the file and press Enter to open the file The base command for Smerge is C-c ^ You will see the conflict and selecting the upper with C-c ^ u and lower with C-c ^ l To select all &amp;lsquo;conflicting&amp;rsquo; changes press C-c ^ a To navigate the conflicts use C-c ^ n and C-c ^ p for next and previous conflict To see all the keybindings use C-c ^ h  With DOOM and hydra:</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>MS Access Shutdown</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/11/09/access-shutdown/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/11/09/access-shutdown/</guid>
			<description>How to shutdown all running Access when you need to do some changes. This is just a summary from Microsoft Docs. The steps are:
Create empty text file  This file will be the key. Name the file to anything like checkfile.</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Merge Selected File</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/30/git-merge-selected-file/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/30/git-merge-selected-file/</guid>
			<description>This guide is from StackOverflow on how to selectively merge files form one branch to another.
Basically it&amp;rsquo;s:
git merge --no-ff --no-commit dev Where dev is the branch you want to merge from into the current branch.
The --no-commit option will stage the files that have been merged by Git without actually committing them.</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Doom tips</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/21/doom-emacs-tips/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/21/doom-emacs-tips/</guid>
			<description>First published date: 2021-04-27
Some tips to learn the keybindings in Doom and Evil in the process of migrating from my vanilla Emacs settings. For overview of keybindings type SPC-h-b-b. Other good references:
 Narra&amp;rsquo;s Blog - Doom Tips and Howtos Org Mode Shortcuts for Emacs Doom Gist of Hjertnes Evil-mode collection  Doom leader-key is SPC and localleader-key is SPC-m.</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>data.table special symbol</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/17/dt-special-symbol/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/17/dt-special-symbol/</guid>
			<description>.N Mult .SD dan .SDcols .I .GRP dan rleid Contoh dari manual  First published: 2017-08-31
Hari ni bersempena Hari kemerdekaan Malaysia ada masa untuk ulang kaji pakej data.table. Hari ni ialah mengenai Special Symbol seperti .N, .I, .GRP, .</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>data.table tips</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/17/datatable_tips/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/17/datatable_tips/</guid>
			<description>First published: 2021-04-20
Some tips for data.table that I came across while googling which might be useful.
Print To print more rows that default can be done with either:
options(datatable.print.topn = 70) print(DT, topn = 70) Using options will implement the changes globally.</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>names attribute</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/17/names-att/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/17/names-att/</guid>
			<description>Sometime an object has attribute names for identification of the value with names instead of index. There are time you need to extract the names of a vector or object. The easiest way is to do:
library(data.table) dt &amp;lt;- cars[1,] setDT(dt) str(dt) dt[, dist := as.</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>SSH-key with Git on Windows</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/06/git-ssh/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 14:11:00 +0200</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/06/git-ssh/</guid>
			<description>First published: 2020-09-29
Generally, these are what I did:
 Install git-with-openssh Create SSH-key Add SSH-key to ssh-agent Create ~/.bashrc for auto-launching ssh-agent  Common problems  Unable to push to origin with this error message.  ssh: Could not resolve hostname personal: Name or service not known fatal: Could not read from remote repository.</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Git Rebase or Reset</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/06/git-rebase/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/06/git-rebase/</guid>
			<description>First published: 2021-08-05
Rebase to previous commit of a sepcific branch ie. master.
git reset --hard origin/master git status or reset to any previous specific commit.
git log --oneline --graph -5 git reset --hard &amp;lt;commit id&amp;gt; git push origin HEAD --force The steps above:</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Clean attributes</title>
			<link>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/03/data-attributes/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://yusbk.github.io/2021/09/03/data-attributes/</guid>
			<description>When reading data from SPSS or Stata into R, the metadata will also be inherited to the dataset. Sometimes it can be useful for extra information, but most of the time it&amp;rsquo;s not needed. To get rid of these metadata then do this:</description>
		</item>
      	
	</channel>
</rss>
